import 'package:vidhan/games/quize/models/question.dart';

const List<Question> questions = [
  Question(
    question: '1. What does Article 24 of the Indian Constitution prohibit?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Child labor',
      'b) Employment of children in hazardous industries',
      'c) Forced labor',
      'd) Discrimination based on age',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '2. Which of the following is specifically banned under Article 24?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Employment of children below the age of 14 years in any factory',
      'b) Employment of children in agricultural work',
      'c) Employment of children in family businesses',
      'd) All forms of child labor',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '3. Article 24 is part of which broader category in the Indian Constitution?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Fundamental Rights',
      'b) Directive Principles of State Policy',
      'c) Fundamental Duties',
      'd) The Union Government',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '4. What is the significance of Article 24 in promoting child rights?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) It allows for child labor in certain conditions.',
      'b) It aims to protect children from exploitation and hazardous work.',
      'c) It promotes child education only.',
      'd) It restricts children from participating in sports.',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '5. Which article complements Article 24 by providing for the prohibition of trafficking and forced labor?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Article 23',
      'b) Article 22',
      'c) Article 21',
      'd) Article 19',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '6. Which legislative measures have been enacted to enforce Article 24?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) The Child Labour (Prohibition and Regulation) Act, 1986',
      'b) The Juvenile Justice (Care and Protection of Children) Act, 2015',
      'c) The Right to Education Act, 2009',
      'd) All of the above',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '7. What is the age limit specified in Article 24 for prohibiting child labor?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Below 12 years',
      'b) Below 14 years',
      'c) Below 16 years',
      'd) Below 18 years',
    ],
  ),
  
  Question(
    question: '8. How does Article 24 contribute to social justice?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) By allowing child labor in family businesses.',
      'b) By ensuring that children are not exploited for labor.',
      'c) By promoting economic growth through cheap labor.',
      'd) By providing special privileges to employers.',
   ],
   ),

   Question(
     question: "9. Which fundamental right is directly related to the provisions in Article 24?",
     correctAnswerIndex:2,
     options:[
        "a ) Right to equality",
        "b ) Right to freedom",
        "c ) Right against exploitation",
        "d ) Right to education",
     ],
   ),

   Question(
     question: "10. Which case emphasized the importance of Article 24 in protecting children's rights?",
     correctAnswerIndex:1,
     options:[
        "a ) M.C. Mehta v. State of Tamil Nadu",
        "b ) Vishaka v. State of Rajasthan",
        "c ) Maneka Gandhi v. Union of India",
        "d ) Indira Gandhi v. Raj Narain",
     ],
   ),
];